<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Find Your Destination</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="unirii_name">Unirii Square</string>
    <string name="text_timi">Frequently referred to as "Little Vienna," Timisoara is settled on the northern bank of River Bega and lies in its distinct architectural character and vibrant cultural life.</string>
    <string name="text_buc">Bucharest is located in the Southern Romania and is the country’s biggest city. Is the Capital of Romania since 1862 AD. It has an elegant architecture built in the period between the two World Wars, reason for which it used to be called the Little Paris.</string>
    <string name="text_arc">Triumphal arches have a long history dating all the way back to the Roman period. The triumphal arch of Bucharest was originally constructed in wood shortly after Romania gained its independence in 1878. Designed by Petre Antonescu (who was renowned for implementing much of the Neo-Romanian architecture throughout the city), the triumphal arch standing today was unveiled in 1936. Antonescu also designed the Bucharest City Hall, the Oprea Soare House, the Law Faculty Palace and the Student’s Culture House, among other important buildings in Bucharest.</string>
    <string name="program">Monday-Friday: closed                 Saturday-Sunday: 12:00-19:30</string>
    <string name="text_tg_jiu">Targu Jiu lies at the foothills of the Carpathian Mountains, on the banks of the river Jiu. Constantin Brancusi, one of the most influential modern sculptors of the 20th century, was born near Targu Jiu, in Hobita.</string>
    <string name="text_ateneu">The Romanian Athenaeum (Romanian: Ateneul Român) is a concert hall in the center of Bucharest, Romania, and a landmark of the Romanian capital city. Opened in 1888, the ornate, domed, circular building is the city\'s most prestigious concert hall and home of the "George Enescu" Philharmonic and of the George Enescu Festival.</string>
    <string name="hyperlink"><a href="https://www.fge.org.ro/vizitareateteneu">https://www.fge.org.ro/vizitareateteneu</a></string>
    <string name="text_cismigiu">The Cișmigiu Gardens or Cișmigiu Park (Romanian: Grădinile Cișmigiu or Parcul Cișmigiu) are a public park in the center of Bucharest, Romania, spanning areas on all sides of an artificial lake. The garden\'s creation was an important moment in the history of Bucharest.They form the oldest and, at 14.6 hectares, the largest park in city\'s central area.The main entrance is from Elisabeta Boulevard, in front of the General City Hall of Bucharest; there is another major entrance at the Știrbei Vodă Street, near the Crețulescu Palace. The southwestern corner of the park is adjacent to the prestigious Gheorghe Lazăr National College. The park attracts an average of 5,100 visitors on a weekend day.</string>
    <string name="text_parlament">The Palace of the Parliament (Romanian: Palatul Parlamentului), also known as the Republic\'s House (Casa Republicii) or People\'s House/People\'s Palace (Casa Poporului), is the seat of the Parliament of Romania, located atop Dealul Spirii in Bucharest, the national capital. The Palace reaches a height of 84 m has a floor area of 365,000 m2 and a volume of 2,550,000 m3. The Palace of the Parliament is the heaviest building in the world, weighing about 4,098,500,000 kilograms (4.10 million tonnes), also being the second largest administrative building in the world.The building was designed and supervised by chief architect Anca Petrescu, with a team of approximately 700 architects, and constructed over a period of 13 years (1984–97) in Socialist realist and modernist Neoclassical architectural forms and styles, with socialist realism in mind.The Palace was ordered by Nicolae Ceaușescu (1918–1989), the president of Communist Romania and the second of two long-ruling heads of state in the country since World War II, during a period in which the personality cult of political worship and adoration increased considerably for him and his family.</string>
    <string name="text_catedrala">The Orthodox Cathedral (Romanian: Catedrala Ortodoxă), also known as the Metropolitan Cathedral (Romanian: Catedrala Mitropolitană), is a Romanian Orthodox church in Timișoara. The cathedral is the seat of the Archbishopric of Timișoara and the Metropolis of Banat. It is dedicated to the Three Holy Hierarchs, Basil the Great, Gregory the Theologian and John Chrysostom.The history of the cathedral is closely linked to the year 1919, when, on 28 July, Banat was united with Romania. The new Romanian administration took a series of measures to encourage Orthodoxy, neglected by the previous Austro-Hungarian administration, which was only favorable to the Catholic religion. Thus, the Bishopric of Timișoara was created, elevated to the rank of archbishopric in 1939, and in 1947 the Metropolis of Banat was established</string>
    <string name="text_opera">The Romanian National Opera (Romanian: Opera Națională Română) is a public opera and ballet institution in Timișoara, Romania. Subordinated to the Ministry of Culture, it is one of the four national opera companies of Romania.The Romanian National Opera was established by royal decree no. 254 of 30 March 1946, issued by King Michael I.The Opera shares the same building with the Mihai Eminescu National Theatre, the Csiky Gergely Hungarian State Theatre and the German State Theatre.</string>
    <string name="hyperlinkopera"><a href="https://www.ort.ro/ro/Spectacole.html">https://www.ort.ro/ro/Spectacole.html</a></string>
    <string name="text_unirii">Union Square (Romanian: Piața Unirii), also known as Dome Square (Romanian: Piața Domului), is the oldest square in Timișoara. It was named in honor of the Romanian troops that entered Timișoara on 3 August 1919 and established the Romanian administration, thus finalizing the union of Banat with Romania.Union Square, with its colorful buildings and unique architecture is one of the most beautiful squares in Europe.         It\'s one of the bests places for enjoying a morning coffee and a croissant.      Nights are vibrant and during afternoons the terraces and restaurants offer a great variety of menus.</string>
    <string name="hyperlinkmuzeu"><a href="https://muzeuldeartatm.ro/">https://muzeuldeartatm.ro/</a></string>
    <string name="text_muzeu">The National Museum of Art of Timisoara is an art museum located in the Baroque Palace in Timișoara.The museum includes a unique collection of works and personal objects of the painter Corneliu Baba, with 90 pieces. 3 other sections include the contemporary, decorative and European art collections. The museum\'s heritage also includes collections of Romanian, Banatian and religious paintings, these are currently not exhibited due to lack of space. The ground floor is dedicated to temporary exhibitions.</string>
    <string name="text_coloana">In 1934, the great Romanian sculptor Constantin Brâncuşi was invited by Aretia Tătărescu, the president of the National League of Women from Gorj, to design a monument in memory of Romanian soldiers who had fallen during World War I. The monument was cast in iron at Atelierele Centrale Petroșani (central workshops of Petroșani) in September 1937. The Endless Column was inaugurated on 27 October 1938. This monument is part of the trilogy of the monument ensemble from Târgu Jiu, which was created by the great sculptor Constantin Brâncuşi, along with Poarta Sărutului (The Gate of Kiss) and Masa Tăcerii (The Table of Silence).</string>
    <string name="text_masa">The Table of Silence is one of three sculptures which make up Constantin Brancusi\'s monument ensemble in the central park at Targu Jiu in Romania. Commissioned in 1935 and completed three years later, the sculptures pay homage to the Romanian soldiers who fought in the first world war.The Table of the Silence sees a large circular stone table surrounded by twelve hourglass seats, an arrangement which can draw comparisons to the Last Supper and is sometimes referred to as the Apostles Table.</string>
    <string name="text_poarta">The Gate of the Kiss is a stone sculpture, made by Constantin Brâncuși, part of the triptych of the Monumental Ensemble from Târgu Jiu. The work was placed in its place in October 1937 and was carved in the first part of 1938, being finalised on September 20 and inaugurated on October 27, 1938.The Gate of the Kiss, which is located on the alley from the entrance of The City Park, is carved out of porous stone, extracted from the quarries in the surroundings, being composed of thick, parallelepiped columns, which supports an arch with a larger dimension than the columns, having 6.45 m wide, 5.13 m high and 1.69 m thick.On the faces of each column is the symbol of the kiss, two halves of a circle, so characteristic of Brâncuși’s work. The architrave also has this symbol inlaid, as a kind of watermark. In addition, in the watermark there are inlays that bring with a kind of roof of the gate, as if the gate would be covered with shingles. The arch of the gate has a delicate linear ornament: it is a continuity of small arches, and above, on three horizontal lines, we find the continuation of identical oval shapes, as if they were the outline of the face and shoulders.
The kissing gate looks like a triumphal arch, symbolizing the triumph of life over the dead</string>

</resources>